telecomitalia.com 2008-12-05

# Telecom Italia - Group

**[Information note for customers, under the provisions of Art. 13 of the Code on the Protection of Personal Data (Legislative Decree 196/03), following the merger by incorporation of Nuova Tin.it s.r.l. in Telecom Italia S.p.A.](http://www.telecomitalia.it/TIPortale/docs/gruppo/Informativa_generale_ai_clienti_TI_ENG_07.pdf)** (file .pdf, 75 Kb)

**Information note for customers of the services "Chiave unica", under the provisions of Art. 13 of the Code on the Protection of Personal Data (Legislative Decree 196/03), following the merger by incorporation of Nuova Tin.it s.r.l. in Telecom Italia S.p.A.** (file .pdf, 63 Kb)

**Information note for shareholders, under the provisions of Art. 13 of the Code on the Protection of Personal Data (Legislative Decree 196/03)**

**List of data processors**

**Privacy Policy for web users**

This Privacy Policy aims at stating clearly the methods of processing of personal data related to users/visitors of this website.

This information is given in accordance with Article 13 of the [Legislative Decree 196/03](http://www.garanteprivacy.it/garante/document?ID=727068) \- Code for the protection of personal data - to whoever is connecting to Telecom Italia’s Corporate website at the following addresses: [www.telecomitalia.it](http://www.telecomitalia.it/) and [www.telecomitalia.com](http://www.telecomitalia.com/).  
The information applies only to the websites mentioned before and it does not apply to other linked websites users connect to.

The websites [www.telecomitalia.it](http://www.telecomitalia.it/) and [www.telecomitalia.com](http://www.telecomitalia.com/) are property of and managed by Telecom Italia S.p.A.  
Telecom Italia S.p.A. guarantees the respect of the law regarding the protection of personal data (Legislative Decree 196/03), as stated in the [Code of Ethics](http://www.telecomitalia.it/TIPortale/docs/investor/codice_etico_marzo2004_eng.pdf) of the Telecom Italia Group.

Web users and visitors must read carefully this Privacy Policy before sending any personal information and/or filling in any electronic form posted on this website.

**Types of personal data and purposes for their processing**

_1) Data concerning the web-surfing_

Computer systems and software procedures on which this website is based are made so that they get, during their ordinary activity, information and personal data that are later sent implicitly through the web by systems based on the Internet protocol.

The gathered information concerns data that could allow to identify web users/visitors by associating and processing them with other data kept by third parties (such as, for example, the IP address, domain and registration numbers of the computers used by people connecting to the website).

These data are used and processed only for statistic purposes (therefore, they are anonymous) and to check if the website is working correctly. They are deleted as soon as they have been processed in such a way.  
Data concerning web contacts are not stored for a longer period than seven days except for any need of checking computer crimes damaging the website.  
No information coming from the web service will ever be either communicated or disseminated.

_2) Data provided spontaneously by users/visitors_

If users/visitors connecting to this website send their personal data in order to use some services or to make requests through e-mail, Telecom Italia gathers their addresses and/or any other personal data, which will be processed exclusively to fulfil the demand or to provide the requested service.

Personal data provided by web users/visitors will be communicated to third parties only in case it is necessary to comply with their requests.

_3) Cookies_

Cookies for the transmission of personal data are not used and neither are used any so-called persistent cookies, that is systems for the tracking of users.

The use of the so-called session cookies (that, in any case, are not stored persistently on the user’s computer and are deleted automatically as soon as the browser is shut down) is strictly limited to the purpose of transmitting data (made up of random numbers created by the server) identifying the specific session and necessary to allow a safe and efficient website surfing.  
The so-called session cookies used in this website avoid any other computer methods that could potentially compromise the privacy about users’web-surfing and they do not make it possible to obtain personal data identifying the specific user.

**Methods of data processing**

Data are processed both through computer-based tools (such as electronic procedures) and manually (such as on paper-based procedures) only for the limited time period necessary for the purposes according to which they have been gathered and, anyway, in compliance with the related law.

**Optional communication of personal data**

Apart from what has been specified previously about navigation data, web users/visitors can decide they want to provide their personal data. Not communicating them only implies that users’requests will not be fulfilled.

**Data controller, data processors and classes of people in charge**

The Data controller is Telecom Italia S.p.A. – headquartered in Piazza degli Affari, 2, 20123 Milan. For the updated list of data processors click here.

Inside the company, the personal data will be processed by the employees in charge of the functions mentioned in the list before. They are “persons in charge of the processing” of personal data under the control of the Data processor.

**Rights of data subjects**

The people whom the personal data refer to have the right to have it confirmed whether their data exist and are stored or not and to know about their content and origin, to check if their data are correct and to ask for their integration, update or correction (according to Article 7 of the [Legislative Decree 196/03](http://www.garanteprivacy.it/garante/document?ID=727068)).

In accordance with that article they can require to have their data deleted, made anonymous or blocked if they are used in violation of the law. Moreover, they can anyway oppose their processing for legitimate reasons.
